YASIR MUSA

(925) 529-5030 | Yasiralhassan82@gmail.com | Pittsburg, CA https://www.linkedin.com/in/yasir-musa-7bab6046/

Summary

Experienced IT professional, with 11 years of Technical Support and Network Administration experience, and 2 years as a freelancer. **Seeking a Temp Work, Contract, fulltime role in the IT space** where I can continue to grow and contribute to the firm's success.

Skills

Soft Skills: Team-Player, People's Person, Calm under Pressure, Communicative, Analytical Thinker **Technical Skills:** MS Windows Servers, HP Servers, VMware, Cisco Switches and Routers, Storage Area Network (SAN), Firewalls (Fortinet, Netasq)

Languages: Proficient in English, High proficient in Arabic as a Native language.

Work Experience

Freelancer | Khartoum, Sudan

Network Engineer | 03/2020 - 06/2021

- As a freelancer provided customers with consultation and quotes related to adding CCTV security systems to their homes and businesses.
- Provided complete installation services including recommendations on integrating HW & SW peripherals that would improve user interface such as monitors and alerts.

Qatar National Bank | Khartoum, Sudan Network Administrator | 09/2014 - 03/2020

- Managed the firm's IT infrastructure including the local and global interconnectivity, ensuring network stability customer information security.
- Worked closely with internal and external auditors and ensured compliance with all banking standards.
- Managed the firm's IT assets varying from workstations, cables, monitors to other PC peripherals.
- Monitored the operation reports of all ATMs in the bank network and reported any instability issues.

Achievements:

Received a corporate recognition award for independently upgrading QNB NCR ATMs without support from external vendors.

Al Nile Bank of Commerce & Development | Khartoum, Sudan Network Engineer | 01/2009 – 08/2014

- Managed a data center and its equipment including servers, routers, switches, UPS units, DC Cooling, and DC environmental monitoring system.
- Provided efficient technical support and solutions to over 400 employees at the Bank's HQ and 38 other branches.

Achievements:

Receive Organization recognition in making substantial saving regarding Data Center migration Project and Deploying New Firewall and Upgrading Windows Servers at the HQ and all branches.

Education & Certifications:

Bachelor of Science in Electrical & Computer Engineering

University of Science & Technology | Khartoum, Sudan | 2006

Certificates:

CompTIA. Security + SY0-601 Certified: Valid to 12/22/2024

Zoom Tech. | Hyderabad | 2006: CCNA, Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP), Microsoft Certified System Administrator (MCSA) & Microsoft Certified System Engineer (MCSE)

LKS | Khartoum | 2011: Linux Red Hat

Knowledge Integration and Innovation Training Center | Khartoum | 2015:

Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert